<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>






<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Sandldan</title>
        <link>https://sandldan.com/</link>
        <description>Personal website of Sandldan.</description>
        <generator>Hugo 0.80.0 https://gohugo.io/</generator>
        
            <language>en</language>
        
        
            <managingEditor>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</managingEditor>
        
        
            <webMaster>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</webMaster>
        
        
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 22:01:01 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate>
        
            <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss&#43;xml" href="https://sandldan.com/rss.xml" />
        
        
            <item>
                <title>Book - Drive</title>
                <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/drive/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sandldan.com/posts/books/drive/</guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:33:02 &#43;0200</pubDate>
                
                    <author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
                
                
                
                    <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/books/drive/drive.jpg&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great book for managers and organizational leaders to read. Studies motivation at work, extrinsic vs intrinsic motivations. The first chapter lays out the hypothesis while the rest of the chapters tries to back this up through various examples, the last chapter instead takes a very practical path - listing actionable strategies for many different situations, also including a nice further reading list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My summary of the first chapter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work can be categorized into two categories; algorithmic and heuristic, the former relates to basic tasks that have a set of instructions and will always follow the same logical path. Heuristic on the other hand is a lot more open ended requiring creativity and problem solving abilities. Motivating someone doing algorithmic work is relatively easy, carrot and stick approach is mostly enough. Motivating someone doing heuristic work is different, here the work itself has an intrinsic value - solving puzzles, expressing creativity can itself be rewarding enough, applying the same rules for algorithmic work motivation can be detrimental. Doing something inherently interesting for fear of punishment or hope for reward can instead remove the individual&amp;rsquo;s inherent desire and interest in the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
When money is used as an external reward for some activity, the subjects lose intrinsic interest for the activity.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Rewards can deliver a short-term boost - just as a jolt of caffeine can keep you cranking for a few more hours. But the effect wears off - and, worse, can reduce a person’s longer-term motivation to continue the project.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
One who is interested in developing and enhancing intrinsic motivation in children, employees, students, etc., should not concentrate on external-control systems such as monetary rewards.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
People in the open-source movement haven’t taken vows of poverty. For many, participation in these projects can burnish their reputations and sharpen their skills, which can enhance their earning power.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Routine work can be outsourced or automated; artistic, empathic, nonroutine work generally cannot.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
He tells prospective employees: “If you need me to motivate you, I probably don’t want to hire you.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Rewards, by their very nature, narrow our focus. That’s helpful when there’s a clear path to a solution. They help us stare ahead and race faster.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Those artists who pursued their painting and sculpture more for the pleasure of the activity itself than for extrinsic rewards have produced art that has been socially recognized as superior.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
In environments where extrinsic rewards are most salient, many people work only to the point that triggers the reward - and no further.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Ensure that the baseline rewards - wages, salaries, benefits, and so on - are adequate and fair. Without a healthy baseline, motivation of any sort is difficult and often impossible.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Rewards do not undermine people’s intrinsic motivation for dull tasks because there is little or no intrinsic motivation to be undermined.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
In a Results-Only Work Environment (ROWE) workplace, people don’t have schedules. They show up when they want. They don’t have to be in the office at a certain time - or any time, for that matter. They just have to get their work done. How they do it, when they do it, and where they do it is up to them.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Resist the temptation to control people - and instead do everything we can to reawaken their deep-seated sense of autonomy.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
People working in self-organized teams are more satisfied than those working in inherited teams.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
A healthy society - and healthy business organizations - begins with purpose and considers profit a way to move toward that end or a happy by-product of its attainment.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
If someone is bored with his current assignment, see if he can train someone else in the skills he’s already mastered. Then see if he can take on some aspect of a more experienced team member’s work.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Get compensation right - and then get it out of sight. Effective organizations compensate people in amounts and in ways that allow individuals to mostly forget about compensation and instead focus on the work itself.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/books/">Books</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/psychology/">Psychology</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/self-improvement/">Self improvement</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/motivation/">Motivation</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Book - Black Box Thinking</title>
                <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/black-box-thinking/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sandldan.com/posts/books/black-box-thinking/</guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 23:42:44 &#43;0100</pubDate>
                
                    <author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
                
                
                
                    <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/books/bbt/bbt.jpg&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started reading this book with the wrongful assumption that it would be technology focused, I had been led to believe this as the book has been mentioned in those circles many times. So what is the book actually about? Failure - and what happens when we can successfully keep learning from failure. The book takes the reader through a mix of interviews, stories and science to convincingly connect it&amp;rsquo;s narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests the book draws upon successful real world areas where we&amp;rsquo;ve been able to implement a system where failures are not ignored but embraced as the learning opportunitites they are, aviation is as safe as it is because of this. The justice system as well as medical institutions are two examples where there&amp;rsquo;s still a resistance to learning from failures. A respected professional with a lot of experience in their field can have an extremely hard time owning up to their mistakes, it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to ignore and come up with excuses instead of losing face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cognitive dissonance, pride, experience, time, environment and group think can all make it incredibly hard to fully appreciate mistakes and take corrective measures. If a group of people belonging to a cult or conspiracy theory is proven conclusively wrong it&amp;rsquo;s likely that they won&amp;rsquo;t correct themselves but instead double down on their conviction, this because the alternative has become too hard to face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author weaves everything together through antrophology, psychology and history - to create a convincing theory where the greatest successes in any field is built on the learnings of failures, the more efficient the feedback loop is the faster anything can be improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world is extremely complex, discoveries, events and accidents might seem certain in retrospect but before conception they were all but. Celebrating a genius mind is a compelling human narrative - but what&amp;rsquo;s not shown is the huge amount of experimentation, failures and pure accident. A pundit can make the most complex and unlikely scenarios sound all but inevitable after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly recommend this book no matter what your background is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Failure is a means - sometimes the only means - of learning, progressing and becoming more creative. This is a hallmark of science, where errors point to how theories can be reformed; of sport, where practice could be defined as the willingness to clock up well-calibrated mistakes; of aviation, where every accident is harnessed as a means of driving system safety.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Most closed loops exist because people deny failure or try to spin it. With pseudosciences the problem is more structural. They have been designed, wittingly or otherwise, to make fsilure impossible. Thst is why, to their adherents, they sre do mesmerising. they sre compatible with everything that happens. But that also means they cannot learn feom anything.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Errors can be thought of as the gap between what we hoped would happen, and what actually did happen.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Failure is inevitable in a complex world. Thus is precisely why learning from mistakes is so imperative.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
It is those who are the most publicly associated with their predictions, whose livelihoods and egos are bound up with their expertise, who are most likely to reframe their mistakes - and who are thus least likely to learn from them
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
People are much quicker to try and confirm their theories than to disprove them .
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Cognitive dissonance occurs when mistakes sre too threatening to admit to, so they sre reframed or ignored. This can be thought of the internal fear of failure: how we struggle to admit mistakes to ourselves.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
it is possible to make significant progress against the biggest problem in the world through the accumulation of a set of small steps, each well thought out, carefully tested, and judiciously implemented
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Every error, every flaw, every failure, however small, is a marginal gain in disguise
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
When we are dealing with complexity, blaming without proper analysis is one of the most common as well as one of the most perilous things an organization can do. And it restsein part on the erroneous belief that toughness and openness are in conflict with each other. They are not.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/books/">Books</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/psychology/">Psychology</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/self-improvement/">Self improvement</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Book - Homo Deus</title>
                <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/homo-deus/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sandldan.com/posts/books/homo-deus/</guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 12:12:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
                
                    <author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
                
                
                
                    <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/homo-deus/homo-deus.jpg&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sapiens (the first book) is one I quickly recommend to most people, easy to read and will broaden your perspective on what it means to be human. I had high hopes going into Homo Deus but unfortunately it fails to captivate to the same degree. The book towards a few core concepts through disjointed anecdotes and sometimes hyperbolic claims, these concepts do succeed in giving a new high level perspective of where humanity is and where we have the potential of going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choice quotes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
99 per cent of our decisions are made by the highly refined algorithms we call sensations, emotions and desires.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
If you really understand the theory of evolution, you understand that there is no soul.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Rome conquered Greece not because the Romans had larger brains or better tool-making techniques, but because they were able to cooperate more effectively.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Sapiens don’t behave according to a cold mathematical logic, but rather according to a warm social logic. We are ruled by emotions. These emotions are in fact sophisticated algorithms that reflect the social mechanisms of ancient hunter-gatherer bands.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
To study history means to watch the spinning and unravelling of these webs, and to realise that what seems to people in one age the most important thing in life becomes utterly meaningless to their descendants.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
In literate societies people are organised into networks, so that each person is only a small step in a huge algorithm, and it is the algorithm as a whole that makes the important decisions.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
This is the best reason to learn history: not in order to predict the future, but to free yourself of the past and imagine alternative destinies. Of course this is not total freedom – we cannot avoid being shaped by the past. But some freedom is better than none.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Each and every one of us has been born into a given historical reality, ruled by particular norms and values, and managed by a unique economic and political system. We take this reality for granted, thinking it is natural, inevitable and immutable. We forget that our world was created by an accidental chain of events, and that history shaped not only our technology, politics and society, but also our thoughts, fears and dreams. The cold hand of the past emerges from the grave of our ancestors, grips us by the neck and directs our gaze towards a single future. We have felt that grip from the moment we were born, so we assume that it is a natural and inescapable part of who we are. Therefore we seldom try to shake ourselves free, and envision alternative futures.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Yet in truth the lives of most people have meaning only within the network of stories they tell one another.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Sapiens rule the world because only they can weave an intersubjective web of meaning: a web of laws, forces, entities and places that exist purely in their common imagination. This web allows humans alone to organise crusades, socialist revolutions and human rights movements.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
The entire modernity contract can be summarised in a single phrase: humans agree to give up meaning in exchange for power.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
A human culture that believed it already knew everything worth knowing would not bother searching for new knowledge. This was the position of most premodern human civilisations. However, the Scientific Revolution freed humankind from this naïve conviction. The greatest scientific discovery was the discovery of ignorance.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Fundamentalists may repeat the mantra that ‘Islam is the answer’, but religions that lose touch with the technological realities of the day forfeit their ability even to understand the questions being asked.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Within myself, the seeming unity that I take for granted dissolves into a cacophony of conflicting voices, none of which is ‘my true self’.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
The stock exchange is the fastest and most efficient data-processing system humankind has so far created. 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book ends with a short summary of its own concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Science is converging on an all-encompassing dogma, which says that organisms are algorithms, and life is data processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligence is decoupling from consciousness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-conscious but highly intelligent algorithms may soon know us better than we know ourselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three processes raise three key questions, which I hope will stick in your mind long after you have finished this book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are organisms really just algorithms, and is life really just data processing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s more valuable - intelligence or consciousness?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will happen to society, politics and daily life when non conscious but highly intelligent algorithms know us better than we know ourselves?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/books/">Books</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Book - On Writing Well</title>
                <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/writing-well/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sandldan.com/posts/books/writing-well/</guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 19:17:58 &#43;0000</pubDate>
                
                    <author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
                
                
                
                    <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/writing-well/writing-well.jpg&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As early as I can remember I loved reading and writing, I was constantly using my fathers old grey typweriter writing my own adventure stories imagining the future fame I&amp;rsquo;d have to humbly accept. My fictional fame didn&amp;rsquo;t last long as there came a point during my early school years where insecurities and school itself killed my writing spirit. Writing for someone else with the potential of having my thoughts read out loud was the worst thing I knew, I only did the bare minimum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constantly overcomplicating my writing while obsessing over how it would be perceived by others never fully disappeared. This book is the best therapy I&amp;rsquo;ve had to overcome some of this, less so for the technical advice and examples it gives, but more due to the new perspectives around how and why you should write in the first place. It managed to really simplify a lot of my thinking as well as approach to writing itself and it&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ve come to appreciate in a new way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing is a great skill whether it&amp;rsquo;s used personally or professionally, being able to gather and communicate your thoughts in a coherent way is very underrated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Writing is an act of ego and you might as well admit it, write unapologetically for yourself
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Examine every word you put on paper. You&#39;ll find a surprising number that don&#39;t serve any purpose.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Don’t try to visualize the great mass audience. There is no such audience—every reader is a different person.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
There are many good reasons for writing that have nothing to do with being published. Writing is a powerful search mechanism, and one of its satisfactions is to come to terms with your life narrative. Another is to work through some of life’s hardest knocks—loss, grief, illness, addiction, disappointment, failure—and to find understanding and solace.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Constantly ask: what am I trying to say? Then ask: have I said it?
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Are you summarizing because you think they’re too dumb to get the point?
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Dead sentences: The reader can’t visualize anybody performing some activity;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
A difficult problem in a sentence can be solved by simply getting rid of it.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Much of the trouble that writers get into comes from trying to make one sentence do too much work.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Now, what do your readers want to know next? Ask yourself that question after every sentence.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Readers should always feel that you know more about your subject than you’ve put in writing.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Don&#39;t annoy your readers by over-explaining--by telling them something they already know or can figure out. Try not to use words like &#34;surprisingly,&#34; &#34;predictably&#34; and &#34;of course,&#34; which put a value on a fact before the reader encounters the fact. Trust your material.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Most first drafts can be cut by 50 percent without losing any information or losing the author’s voice.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Nobody turns so quickly into a bore as a traveler home from his travels. He enjoyed his trip so much that he wants to tell us all about it—and “all” is what we don’t want to hear. We only want to hear some.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Writing improves in direct ratio to the number of things we can keep out of it that shouldn’t be there.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Nobody can write a decent article about the disappearance of small towns in Iowa; it would be all generalization and no humanity. The writer would have to write about one small town in Iowa and thereby tell her larger story. And even within that one town she would have to reduce her story still further: to one store, or one family, or one farmer.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/books/">Books</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/writing/">Writing</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/self-improvement/">Self improvement</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tattoo</title>
                <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/tattoo/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sandldan.com/posts/tattoo/</guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 22:05:27 &#43;0200</pubDate>
                
                    <author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
                
                
                
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;During my late teenage years I started thinking about getting a tattoo, eventually the thought turned into a fact, a fact without need to be reflected on any longer, it&#39;s been sitting there as a fact all this time until I now at 31 have booked my first appointment. This provoked the former undisputable fact, which decided to morph back into a thought that I can work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I&#39;m not unfamiliar to this happening, who&#39;s able to keep any doubt out when confronted with a permanent decision? I still feel sure of getting the tattoo, but it&#39;s a perfect opportunity to dig deeper to where the doubts or uncertainty actually are coming from&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where did the idea come from?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had the idea for such a long time It&#39;s hard to recall where it started, when reflecting I might be able to come up with a few resons (are they the original ones or just my current interpretations of the past?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i title=&#34;YOLO&#34;&gt;While I live I want to finish a reasonably long todo list&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;I got influenced by people and media around me&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end it&#39;s almost impossible to separate out the external influence, as it has been a passive thought for such a long time it makes it harder to separate my original reasoning from other sources. And even if I could, it&#39;s not like there&#39;s any more value in having the original idea come just from myself. What matters is what I want now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Regret&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking back to the tattoo ideas I had 10 years ago, I would probably not get the same tattoos today, will the same be true 10 years in the future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s tricky... I think the only old ideas that I&#39;d dislike today are anything based on any kind of culture or trend, and my emotion towards it might change a lot after wearing the tattoo for many years as well. I think I early came to the conclusion to get a tattoo from an artist I like and that simply looks good for what it is, trying not to instill too much meaning into it.&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Is it me?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A seemingly obvious question, which feels a bit more complex, am I just copying trends? Influenced by people around me? How will this reflect off of me? I think I enjoy being a blank slate, having a style and presence that can fit in everywhere&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While growing up I quickly removed styles, habits and accents, anything that could be used to read into my interests or background. I enjoyed surprising people who had no idea I was this geeky, that I came from this country, that I&#39;ve done these things. I had a goal of experiencing as much as possible and to do this I felt I had to be able to partially fit in as many contexts as possible, in a way you lose out a bit here, you go broader but not deeper in areas and relations.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Maybe this is where most of my sudden unease is coming from? By getting a permanent tattoo I&#39;m projecting parts of myself in a very visible way. The style, motive and placement of the tattoo will expose something about me that I can&#39;t take back, I can&#39;t control how others perceive it. It&#39;s a bit ironic, by making a part of myself more solid and visible, I feel I might in exchange lose a part of myself, I&#39;m not as much of a blank slate surprise anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;So?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As planned I went to get a tattoo with no hesitations left in my mind, writing these thoughts down definitely helped to untangle myself while achieving a bit deeper insights into my motivations. Maybe it&#39;ll help me in putting part of myself out there without being afraid of how it might be perceived by others, or maybe, just maybe - &lt;i&gt;it&#39;s just a tattoo&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/tattoo/1.jpeg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/tattoo/2.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/life/">Life</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/personal/">Personal</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Book - Weapons of Math Destruction</title>
                <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/weapons-of-math-destruction/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sandldan.com/posts/books/weapons-of-math-destruction/</guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 11:11:35 &#43;0200</pubDate>
                
                    <author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
                
                
                
                    <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/weapons-of-math-destruction/wmd.webp&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good and short introduction for anyone interested in the subject of big data and its potential negative side effects, I think the core message can be summarized in this quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Big Data processes codify the past. They do not invent the future. Doing that requires moral imagination, and that&#39;s something only humans can provide.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science is nothing new, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think many people are familiar with how its being applied, chances are that you have already been indirectly affected by it, positively or negatively. So how is it being used then? When people try to answer a seemingly simply question with a system, questions like which school is the best? Can I trust this person enough to give a loan? Will this person end up in jail again? Through computers and enough data available we believe we can answer these questions easily, though in reality many of these systems end up as a Weapon of Math Destruction (WMD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time people&amp;rsquo;s own biases and racisms are unintentionally encoded into these systems, for example race might not be an explicit variable but zip codes can make for a near identical substitute. In the end these systems end up working great for many people and can go horribly wrong for others, do you live in a bad neighbourhood but have no criminal record? Chances are you&amp;rsquo;ll be judged more harshly than someone from a different background. In the race for improved school ratings tuition fees is not a variable which has contributed to the astronomical increase in fees for students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book starts with defining what a WMD is and continues by going through various examples in great detail. it kind of stops a bit abruptly after this without much further elaboration. Most of the examples throughout the book are very US-centric, where regulation is usually more reactive rather than pre-emptive, compared to Europe, as far as I know these systems are not as widely adopted or even usable in Europe. I&amp;rsquo;d be very interested to know more of such systems being used here as it&amp;rsquo;s not something that&amp;rsquo;s generally widely reported on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom line, great short read that can open up your eyes to something that feels obvious in retrospect, which is one of the better results after finishing a book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/books/">Books</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/technology/">Technology</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Book - Technically Wrong</title>
                <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/technically-wrong/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sandldan.com/posts/books/technically-wrong/</guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 11:11:35 &#43;0200</pubDate>
                
                    <author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
                
                
                
                    <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/technically-wrong/technically-wrong.jpg&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this book would&amp;rsquo;ve been slightly better for my past self to have read, with the potential issue of my past self not being fully reciprocal to the content nor interested enough to pick up the book in the first place. I&amp;rsquo;d blame myself for being too enthusiastic about the tech industry and its seemingly endless possibilities as well as being too focused on my own career path. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget to stop and reflect on your own privileges and empathising with others situation&amp;rsquo;s during your own struggles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is a great read for anyone working in tech or anyone who&amp;rsquo;s interacting with parts of the tech industry (which is most people these days). The book succinctly breaks down the broken feedback loops of biases, ethical oversights and sexisms littered throughout the tech industry specifically. It&amp;rsquo;s not something most of us feel we perpetuate, we&amp;rsquo;re just doing our best to solve interesting problems right? But the problems runs deeper than any single individual, the culture that has been set as precedence by successful companies is non welcoming to outsiders resulting in a lack of diversity which in turn shows itself in how the technology around us is meant to be interacted with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a short read with a lot of anecdotal stories, lacking a bit in deeper insights and advice. If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following the tech industry for a longer time you&amp;rsquo;ve most likely been able to pick up most pieces presented in the book, but you might not pieced everything together in feedback the broad perspective given in this book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/books/">Books</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/technology/">Technology</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sunrise Photography</title>
                <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/sunrise-photographing/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sandldan.com/posts/sunrise-photographing/</guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 20:03:22 &#43;0200</pubDate>
                
                    <author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
                
                
                
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;During quarantine I&#39;ve managed to get up with the sun a few early weekend mornings. Strolling around the city canals before people have reclaimed the streets. The slowly dissipating morning fog of the city is home to a surprisingly active wildlife, birds, fish and cats is the main life grabbing your attention. When back home it feels like I&#39;ve come back from a different world, like a long holiday, this feeling usually sticks with you for the full day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I&#39;ll be able to continue this even after quarantine, with or without a camera. Here&#39;s some of the photos I&#39;ve taken during a few Utrecht mornings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_4835.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DJI_0384.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DJI_0385.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DJI_0391-2.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DJI_0398.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_47321.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_4750.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_4777.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Creative social distancing guidelines&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_4819.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_4823.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_4870.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_4871.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_4873.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_4889.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_4894.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_4908.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/showcase/DSC_4931.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/photography/">Photography</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/utrecht/">Utrecht</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://sandldan.com/tags/the-netherlands/">The Netherlands</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
