<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Sandldan</title>
    <link>https://sandldan.com/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Sandldan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 21:44:43 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sandldan.com/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book - Drive</title>
      <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:33:02 +0200</pubDate><author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
      <guid>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/drive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/books/drive/drive.jpg&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great book for managers and organizational leaders to read. Studies motivation at work, extrinsic vs intrinsic motivations. The first chapter lays out the hypothesis while the rest of the chapters tries to back this up through various examples, the last chapter instead takes a very practical path - listing actionable strategies for many different situations, also including a nice further reading list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book - Black Box Thinking</title>
      <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/black-box-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 23:42:44 +0100</pubDate><author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
      <guid>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/black-box-thinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/books/bbt/bbt.jpg&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started reading this book with the wrongful assumption that it would be technology focused, I had been led to believe this as the book has been mentioned in those circles many times. So what is the book actually about? Failure - and what happens when we can successfully keep learning from failure. The book takes the reader through a mix of interviews, stories and science to convincingly connect it&amp;rsquo;s narrative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book - Homo Deus</title>
      <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/homo-deus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 12:12:41 +0200</pubDate><author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
      <guid>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/homo-deus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/homo-deus/homo-deus.jpg&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sapiens (the first book) is one I quickly recommend to most people, easy to read and will broaden your perspective on what it means to be human. I had high hopes going into Homo Deus but unfortunately it fails to captivate to the same degree. The book towards a few core concepts through disjointed anecdotes and sometimes hyperbolic claims, these concepts do succeed in giving a new high level perspective of where humanity is and where we have the potential of going.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book - On Writing Well</title>
      <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/writing-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 19:17:58 +0000</pubDate><author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
      <guid>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/writing-well/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/writing-well/writing-well.jpg&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As early as I can remember I loved reading and writing, I was constantly using my fathers old grey typweriter writing my own adventure stories imagining the future fame I&amp;rsquo;d have to humbly accept. My fictional fame didn&amp;rsquo;t last long as there came a point during my early school years where insecurities and school itself killed my writing spirit. Writing for someone else with the potential of having my thoughts read out loud was the worst thing I knew, I only did the bare minimum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book - Weapons of Math Destruction</title>
      <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/weapons-of-math-destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 11:11:35 +0200</pubDate><author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
      <guid>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/weapons-of-math-destruction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/weapons-of-math-destruction/wmd.webp&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good and short introduction for anyone interested in the subject of big data and its potential negative side effects, I think the core message can be summarized in this quote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;Big Data processes codify the past. They do not invent the future. Doing that requires moral imagination, and that&#39;s something only humans can provide.&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data science is nothing new, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think many people are familiar with how its being applied, chances are that you have already been indirectly affected by it, positively or negatively. So how is it being used then? When people try to answer a seemingly simply question with a system, questions like which school is the best? Can I trust this person enough to give a loan? Will this person end up in jail again? Through computers and enough data available we believe we can answer these questions easily, though in reality many of these systems end up as a Weapon of Math Destruction (WMD).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book - Technically Wrong</title>
      <link>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/technically-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 11:11:35 +0200</pubDate><author>andre@sandldan.com (Sandldan)</author>
      <guid>https://sandldan.com/posts/books/technically-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sandldan.com/images/posts/technically-wrong/technically-wrong.jpg&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think this book would&amp;rsquo;ve been slightly better for my past self to have read, with the potential issue of my past self not being fully reciprocal to the content nor interested enough to pick up the book in the first place. I&amp;rsquo;d blame myself for being too enthusiastic about the tech industry and its seemingly endless possibilities as well as being too focused on my own career path. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget to stop and reflect on your own privileges and empathising with others situation&amp;rsquo;s during your own struggles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
